Guide to the Alan Sondheim Papers MSS.267
Fales Library and Special Collections
Alan Sondheim Papers
1965-2002
Fales Library and Special Collections
Sondheim, Alan
MSS.267
55.5 Linear Feet in 52 records cartons, 6 flat boxes, 1 small cassette box, and 1 large reel
95 sound tape reels 94 1/4" audio reels and 1 1/2" audio reel
215 audiocassettes 214 compact cassettes and 1 microcassette
45 film reels 15 8mm films, 4 super8 films, 21 16mm films, 4 35mm films, 1 offsite film
87 videoreels (1/2 inch)
100 videocassettes (u-matic)
7 videocassettes (betamax)
1 videocassettes (betacam)
124 videocassettes (vhs)
3 videocassettes (minidv)
2 sound discs (vinyl)
21 electronic discs (cd-rom)
16 dvd-r disks
2 3.5" floppy disks
1 media elements 1 hard drive
9 items 9 artifacts
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Alan Sondheim in April, 2010; the accession number associated with this collection is 2009-267.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact [Fales, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596] with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Cyberspace |x Political aspects.; Art and the internet -- Exhibitions; Computer art.; Digital art |z United States.; New media art.; Video art -- United States.; Experimental films -- United States; Slides (Photography); Gender identity -- United States; Feminist theory.
- Series I. Written Work
- Series II. Visual Art
  - WHERE DID HE GET THAT PIPE... by Mike Metz, 1985 (Box 27)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    This art piece is made of cast aluminum.
- Series III. Musical Recordings
  - 121 Back - S-Original, Undated (Box 25, Quarter inch audio reel 267_089)
  - 20,000 / 1 / 20,000, Undated (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_230, Box 13, Audiocassette 267_187)
  - 3rd Heather Session, Undated (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_244)
  - "349"; "Live Mix" (on WREK radio); Jarboe; Chris Schwartz; Arthur Davis, Undated (Box 15, Audiocassette 267_465)
    The audiocassette sits in a large hand-painted case portraying a red and black silhouette on a deep purple background.
  - 52, Undated; cuid30311 (Box 25, Quarter inch audio reel 267_130)
  - A General Description of the World, Alan Sondheim, Undated; cuid30312 (Box 25, Quarter inch audio reel 267_129)
  - Adrian Pipui and Alan Sondheim, Undated (Box 14, Audiocassette 267_343)
  - Alan Sondheim, March 19, 1974 (Box 14, Audiocassette 267_365)
  - Alan Sondheim, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_201)
    Scope and Contents
    Note says "Jona Lewie, Ry Cooder, Bop Til You Drop"
  - Alan Sondheim - 2nd Duplicate, 1971-1975 (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_172)
    Note says "plus background references." Roll 3 is dated February 7, 1975 and Roll 4 is dated February 10, 1975.
  - Alan Sondheim Interview - L. Thornton, L. Peckham, D. de la Cerde, T. Zummer, February 22, 1987 (Box 14, Audiocassette 267_360)
  - Alan's Tape, Undated (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_300)
  - All 770, October 29, 1967; cuid30309 (Box 25, Quarter inch audio reel 267_132)
  - Alvin Lucier - Music on a Long Thin Wire, circa 1992 (Box 14, Audiocassette 267_355)
  - Andes, Undated (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_225)
  - Andy / Alan on Thater [Illegible], Undated (Box 14, Audiocassette 267_358)
  - Andy James, Undated (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_228)
  - Angeline Soundtrack, Undated (Box 14, Audiocassette 267_336)
  - Antigone Tape, 1967 (Box 23, Quarter inch audio reel 267_099)
  - The Antithesis to Recessive Ideologies 12345 (music) 54321, February 4, 1978; cuid30303 (Box 24, Quarter inch audio reel 267_124)
    Audio reel 267_124 identified as moldy on December 6, 2021. Theis item is currently isolated from other items by housing it in a polyethylene bag with a desiccated board and RH monitor strip. If this strip indicates an RH greater than 50%, the Preservation department should be contacted ASAP. Do not open this packaging without contacting the Preservation Department.
  - Arrangement #1 - Electronic, Undated (Box 25, Quarter inch audio reel 267_055)
  - Ascending Pulse Echo / Descending, Undated (Box 14, Audiocassette 267_361)
  - Background Music, Undated (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_260)
    Other labels on the tape say, "Home Movie Soundtrack" and "Mix for Millennium."
  - Background Music 2: 123 Damaged Life / Despair Soundtrack, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_163)
  - Background Music with Voice, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_158)
  - Background / Tango, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_175)
  - Bantok Rock, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_151)
  - Bass Recorder Breath Piano, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_188)
  - Because I'm a Woman Jarboe, 1984 (Box 15, Audiocassette 267_464)
    The audiocassette sits in a large hand-painted case that portrays a woman gazing downwards.
  - Being With Him - Clara, Undated (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_277)
  - Beme Seed, Undated (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_305, Box 15, Audiocassette 267_463)
  - Biblical Piece Using Language and Gesenus Dictionary [first line of Genesis]: Spoken, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_177)
  - Big Stick Crack'n'Drag and Lizzy Mercer Descloux / Factrix, Cazzaza, California Bablyon, Undated (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_309)
  - Blues, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_199)
  - Bob Leigh Interview, Undated; cuid30292 (Box 24, Quarter inch audio reel 267_113)
  - Bohm, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_150)
    Note says "foghorn."
  - Boredoms - "Pop Tatari", Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_169)
  - Bottle Hill, Undated (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_218)
  - Brasil I, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_196)
  - Breath Piece, Undated (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_205)
  - Brox / Bicks, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_160)
    Note says "Moscow ETC"
  - Buffalo City Council Sample, Undated (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_223)
  - Buffalo Gals, Undated (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_219)
  - C#-D Melodica, Guitar Filled Intervals, Lips Echo, Undated (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_231)
  - Cadere in Memorium with Andy Karp / Arithmetic of Signifiers, 1983-1984 (Box 14, Audiocassette 267_368)
    Microcassette
  - Cadererlin / Memories [Illegible], Undated (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_284)
  - Carey Driving Young Durk [Illegible], Undated (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_293)
  - Casio, Undated (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_226)
  - Cauldron by Alan Sondheim, Helena Espvall and Azure Carter, 2011 (Box 22, Sound disc--vinyl 267_788)
    This LP features Alan Sondheim on acoustic-electric guitar, guzheng, oud, alpine zither, and ukulele; Azure Carter's voice; and Helena Espvall on cello. It was produced by Fire Museum Records in association with Tequila Sunrise Records.
  - Chant, Undated (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_250)
  - Christen Hennui and Alan Sondheim on Topores, NYC at the Waters, August 31, 1975 (Box 14, Audiocassette 267_352)
    The cassette's handwritten label is difficult to read.
  - Christians in a Dead World, Undated (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_299)
  - Citizen Hostage Big Talk #1, 1984 (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_239)
  - Clark Coolidge Conversation with Alan Sondheim, Fall, 1966; cuid30301 (Box 24, Quarter inch audio reel 267_123)
  - Compactor Tapes, Undated (Box 25, Quarter inch audio reel 267_088)
  - Computer Operation, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_186)
  - Concert at St. Mark's - Reading, Electronics, Guitar, November 10, 1975 (Box 14, Audiocassette 267_327, 267_363, Box 13, Audiocassette 267_176)
  - Concert with Laurie Audura / Notes on Nancy [Illegible], Undated (Box 14, Audiocassette 267_339)
  - Continuation, Undated (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_274)
  - Conversation with G. H. [Illegible], Undated (Box 14, Audiocassette 267_367)
  - Craw - 3 Songs, Undated (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_314)
  - Cricket, Undated (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_224)
  - Dairy Queen Empire, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_168)
  - Damaged Life - 123 Nicaragua Sex Master, November 30, 1986 (Box 22, Quarter inch audio reel 267_068)
  - Damaged Life / Devo, Undated (Box 14, Audiocassette 267_331)
  - Damaged Life Compilation, August 9, 1986 (Box 25, Quarter inch audio reel 267_072, Box 14, Audiocassette 267_356)
    This tape also includes a duplicate master of "Global Report" by Damaged Life. The tape is reverse wound.
  - Damaged Life - Film Music, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_159)
  - Damaged Life - Flesh, 1987 (Box 25, Quarter inch audio reel 267_102)
  - Damaged Life - Flesh at 123 Club, Undated (Box 14, Audiocassette 267_347)
  - Damaged Life - Global Report, 1986 (Box 22, Quarter inch audio reel 267_067, Box 14, Audiocassette 267_349, 267_350, Box 11, Audiocassette 267_317, Box 13, Audiocassette 267_161)
  - Damaged Life - Lips, 1987 (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_289, 267_316, 267_320)
  - Damaged Life - Live at Intermedia, May 13, 1988 (Box 14, Audiocassette 267_342)
  - Damaged Life - Live at the Starck Club, July 31, 1987 (Box 1, Vhs 267_567, Box 2, U-matic 267_574, Box 3, U-matic 267_596, Box 14, Audiocassette 267_337, 267_340, 267_341)
    According to the tape labels, each tape shows a recording from a different camera. 267_567 and 267_341 are the video and audio from Fran's camera. 267_574 is the "2nd camera, Fran and Rich Gold, silent, to be synced up with Marlis Schmidt's camera (Master)." 267_596 is Marlis Schmidt's camera - it's label also says "2nd tape with sound. Alan Sondheim, Denise de la Cerda, Devonna Walker, Randal Davis, Dallas. Master."
  - Damaged Life - "Machine", February 17, 1986 (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_288)
  - Damaged Life - "Repressive Circuitry", August, 1986 (Box 23, Quarter inch audio reel 267_093)
    Alan Sondheim for Damaged Life: 8/86 Master no noise reduction; modified for continuous play; repressive circuitry; includes foghorn / voice encoding / 'it was fine till he came along' / theory // 'lie' / drumwave/drone/other rhythms/drones; 7.5 ips; full both sides.
  - Damaged Life - "Soot", February 5, 1986 (Box 14, Audiocassette 267_366)
  - Damaged Life - Starck Club Back Tracks, circa 1987 (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_308)
  - Damaged Life - Starck Club Rehearsal, circa 1987 (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_261)
  - Damaged Life - [Square] Dance / Live Alumni Practice, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_162)
    Note says "copy"
  - Damaged Life - "Terrifui," used on Chrysanthemum, Undated (Box 14, Audiocassette 267_372)
  - Damaged Life - "Viva Nicaragua", Undated (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_254)
  - Damaged Life - Wave Improv / Recorder Improv, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_162)
  - Dance, Recorder, Undated (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_248, 267_252)
  - David Anter and Adrian Conversation, Undated (Box 14, Audiocassette 267_345)
  - David Askevold and Alan Sondheim Harmony, Undated (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_264)
  - Dawnja Audio, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_157)
    Note says "Also ETC Music Trans."
  - Delight Slight Light Kiss, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_147)
    Track List in English and Japanese
  - Denise Where Are You?, Undated (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_254)
  - Devo Randy Alan including [illegible] 45 track, Undated (Box 14, Audiocassette 267_332)
  - Devonna, Undated (Box 14, Audiocassette 267_357)
  - Diamanda Galas, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_173)
  - Dieu Reconnaitra Les Siens, Undated (Box 14, Audiocassette 267_335)
    The cassete case has a photo slide attached on the inside, dated November 1988.
  - Dogs Drone Tape - Tape Concerned with Past [Illegible], Undated (Box 25, Quarter inch audio reel 267_058)
  - Domestic and Public Pieces by Derek Bailey, 1975-1976; cuid30316 (Box 25, Quarter inch audio reel 267_136)
    The tape's label reads: "Second, Third, First, Seventh, Fourth - Live in London, May 22, 1975; Kew, Unity Theatre, Queue - At Home with Derek Bailey, January, 1976"
  - Drake Scott, Proper Yearning: Emergency / Catblurph / Believe Coma / Starlit Night / Variations on a Postmortem Orgy / Sister / Gallantry, 1985 (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_156)
    The cassette includes lyrics on folded paper.
  - Drops by Derek Bailey and Andrea Centazzo, April, 1977; cuid30315 (Box 25, Quarter inch audio reel 267_136)
    The tape's label reads: "Drop One: Recapitulation, Reitaration, Rabbits; Drop Two; Tutti Cantabile; Drop Three; Drop Four; Sing, Sing, Sing; How Long Has This Been Going On?; Derek Bailey - Guitar; Andrea Centazzo - Percussion; Moruzzo, Italy; April, 1977"
  - Dual News, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_181)
  - Duleumi [illegible] Improvised Piano, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_185, Box 24, Quarter inch audio reel 267_112)
    Note says "with Contact Microphone"
  - Dupe of Recent [Illegible], Undated (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_245)
  - The East is Red, Undated (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_292)
  - Echo on Bagpipe, Guitar (Shenai), Undated; cuid30304 (Box 24, Quarter inch audio reel 267_125)
  - EL Balance Piece, Undated (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_275)
  - Electronic Improvisation, Undated (Box 25, Quarter inch audio reel 267_082)
  - Electronic Music, Undated (Box 25, Quarter inch audio reel 267_066)
    A note on the tape says "whose electronic music?"
  - Electronic "Water" Tape, Undated; cuid30310 (Box 25, Quarter inch audio reel 267_131)
  - Electronics, Undated (Box Quarantine 1, Quarter inch audio reel 267_795)
  - ESP Record, Undated; cuid30300 (Box 24, Quarter inch audio reel 267_121)
  - ESP Sampler with you on it, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_164)
    Note says "Happy Chanukah Alan"
  - France / Dance Master, Undated (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_272)
  - From the Theatre Piece, Undated (Box 23, Quarter inch audio reel 267_080)
  - The Garden Planet Revisited by Jacki Apple, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_202)
  - Geoff Dugan - The Aluminum Hallway, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_171)
    The cassette includes a tracklist.
  - Geoff Dugan - Base Animal, 1989 (Box 14, Audiocassette 267_373)
  - Glossolalia, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_189, 267_198)
  - Good Electronics, Undated; cuid30290 (Box 24, Quarter inch audio reel 267_111)
  - Great Electronics, Undated (Box 24, Quarter inch audio reel 267_086)
  - Group Concert Pieces, Undated; cuid30294 (Box 24, Quarter inch audio reel 267_115)
  - Guitar, April, 1975 (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_207)
  - Guitar and Building Resonance, Undated (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_215)
  - Guitar Solo, Manlys, Undated (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_311)
  - Guitar / Sonfist, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_182)
  - Hanni Neyor / Sleepy Volume Estes, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_193)
  - Harmonica / Airline, Undated (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_276)
  - Harmonics - [Illegible] ETC, November, 2002 (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_315)
  - Hazel Nuts - Alvin Curran, May 9, 1971 (Box 25, Quarter inch audio reel 267_062)
  - Heavy Echo with Guitar - Hiss, Undated (Box 23, Quarter inch audio reel 267_042)
  - Hiwood, Undated (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_218)
  - Hollywood Boulevard Sounds / Carrie on Jim / Short Section / Piano Modulation, Undated (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_294)
  - Hornpipes Firenze Concert (Bill, Viola, Art, Topes), April, 1975 (Box 14, Audiocassette 267_326)
  - Hornpipes Practice Session with Bill Viola, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_160)
  - Horns, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_184)
  - Hot Mud, Undated (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_287)
  - Humans ETC, 2000 (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_148)
  - I. Sections Wound Backwards / Magnetic Tape Readout Piece, Undated (Box 25, Quarter inch audio reel 267_061)
  - I'm Sorry I… Heather / Alan, Undated (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_234, Box 14, Audiocassette 267_371)
  - Improvisations by Derek Bailey and David Holland, January, 1971; cuid30314 (Box 25, Quarter inch audio reel 267_137)
    The tape's label reads, "Improvisations; Derek Bailey - Guitar; David Holland - Cello; Live in London, January, 1971"
  - International Folk Music Compilation, October 31, 1969 (Box 23, Quarter inch audio reel 267_097)
    This recording includes songs from Ethiopia, Romania, Hungary, Lithuania, Persia, and Colombia. The tape has a label from the Department of Music at Brown University,
  - Jacques Cartier, Undated (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_296)
  - Jarboe, Undated (Box 15, Audiocassette 267_462)
  - Joanna - Mighty Risen Plea Records, Undated (Box 14, Audiocassette 267_346)
  - Ken Kesey and Merry Pranksters, Undated (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_310)
  - Kim Il Sung 70th Birthday - Radio North Korea Pyongyang, April 15, 1982 (Box 14, Audiocassette 267_330)
    The label also says "9977 on dial - 3:00am - 4:10am L.A."
  - Kim Il Sung ETC Soundtrack Music, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_154)
  - Kimilsungism [Illegible] Analysis I, Undated (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_280)
  - Krishnamurti and Me, Undated (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_310)
  - Koto Tummy, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_183)
  - Last Fighter in the Bolshevick Revolution, Undated (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_227)
  - Last Night Mix Tape, Undated (Box 25, Quarter inch audio reel 267_069, 267_070, 267_073, 267_083)
  - Late Piece with Synthesizer, June, Undated; cuid30297 (Box 24, Quarter inch audio reel 267_118)
  - Laura and Alan, Undated (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_263)
  - Lockin' in Harmonies / Normal Voice Encoding at Subharmonies, Undated (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_212)
  - Long Devonner Improvisation Material All Side, Undated (Box 14, Audiocassette 267_354)
  - Lynn Hughes full script, news special, Undated (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_249)
  - Mandolin, Piano, ETC, and Reading into Piano, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_192)
    Note says "Piano / Mandolin / Reading into Piano ETC"
  - Marcia Resnick, Undated (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_221)
  - Mariel Boatlift - Nighlirr [Illegible], November 23, 1987 (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_281)
  - Mariner, Undated (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_222)
  - Master / Slave Relationship: Sound of Pig Music #82, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_145)
  - Matrix, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_180)
  - Meta Notes / Heartbeat Tape, Undated (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_266)
  - Meta Thinktank, 1972 (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_152)
  - Michael Oppitz Interview, May 4, 1986 (Box 14, Audiocassette 267_359)
  - Middle 6, Middle 14, Undated (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_243)
  - Mighty Risen Plea, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_170)
  - Minntemen, Undated (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_206)
  - Mr Mrs Accident - Cornfield Ears, 1987 (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_303)
  - Mouse Music, Undated (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_253)
  - Murmurs, Undated (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_255)
  - Music [illegible], Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_178)
  - Music by Terry Firenze / Music with Teddy Fox, Bill, Viola Florence, Undated (Box 14, Audiocassette 267_325)
  - Music for its Erhea [Illegible], Undated (Box 23, Quarter inch audio reel 267_047)
  - Muzak - QtP, Undated (Box 14, Audiocassette 267_370)
  - New Tape, Undated (Box 23, Quarter inch audio reel 267_045)
  - New York Women Tape, August 8, 1975 (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_181, 267_195)
  - Niagra Falls, Heather College, Undated (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_246)
  - Nostalgic Tape, Undated (Box 23, Quarter inch audio reel 267_075)
  - Notes on Aesthetics, European and Amer. [illegible], Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_178)
  - Notes Then Mandolin, Undated (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_319)
  - NSCAD Guitar / Pulse Concert / Dual Conversation / part NSCAD Guitar Concert / Patternless loud Drumming / fast / Pattern Change ETC, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_180)
  - O to 253: Sound FM; Memory Film, Undated (Box 14, Audiocassette 267_348)
  - Object Into Sound - Translation Utilizing Half-Inch Grid, Undated (Box 25, Quarter inch audio reel 267_077)
  - Object Into Sound - Translation Using Five Inch Grid, September 22, 1969 (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_302)
  - Old Group Streusto [Illegible] Pro-Recording, Undated (Box 23, Quarter inch audio reel 267_044)
  - Old Tape with Gretch Guitar, Undated; cuid30293 (Box 24, Quarter inch audio reel 267_114)
    A note on the tape says, "Beautiful - don't lose."
  - Organ / Hughes / News, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_200)
  - Organ Tape: Eva Sue Szela, URI, circa 1966 (Box 23, Quarter inch audio reel 267_098)
  - Organ Tape: URI Thomas, Church Organ, 1966; cuid30306 (Box 24, Quarter inch audio reel 267_128)
  - Organ Tape for Reed Point, Undated (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_238)
  - Patternless Tap Dancing, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_188)
  - Patricia Rogers, Undated; cuid30302 (Box 24, Quarter inch audio reel 267_122)
  - Paul B / N. Kitchel Notes + Notes on Pieces, Eyeing, Novel, Etc., Undated (Box 14, Audiocassette 267_333)
  - Paula Claire and the Paxton Group Performances, Undated (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_208)
    This tape contains poetry and musical performances by Paula Claire and the Paxton Group, which includes Steven Paxton, John Griffith, Ray Dillard, and Cynthia Cole. Performances include "Spiderunes," "The Dundee Telgrams, "The Patmost Poems," "Still Life," "Zen Inscriptions," "Through Glass," and "OIF."
  - Pia Zastera, Undated (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_209)
  - Piano, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_179)
  - Piece: Notes on Linguistic Pieces, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_189)
  - Political Third Tape, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_203)
  - Post-Conceptual Act, RISD, March 19, 1974 (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_270)
  - Potential Propaganda…, Undated (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_297)
  - The Quran, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_146)
  - Rain, Undated (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_225)
  - Rapping, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_190)
  - The Raven / The History of Album Rock [Empty Audiotape Box], Undated (Box 25, Box 267_108)
  - Reagan Shooting / Music for Brazil, September, 1979 (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_291)
  - Reed Point / British Census of Hallucinations, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_196)
  - "Requiem Digitatem" by Mia Lipner, a special audio installment for Vol 9, No. 1, Issue 17: "Sexuality & Cyberspace", 1996 (Box 14, Audiocassette 267_353)
  - Reversed Dulemei [illegible] Master, Undated; cuid30299 (Box 24, Quarter inch audio reel 267_120)
  - Rhythm Pieces, August, 1986 (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_250)
  - RISO Concert Tape, Undated; cuid30307 (Box 24, Quarter inch audio reel 267_134)
  - RISD Semi-Electronic with Guitar Feedback, February 2, 1971 (Box 23, Quarter inch audio reel 267_100)
  - Ritual All 770 I, Undated (Box 23, Quarter inch audio reel 267_076)
  - Ritual All 770 II, Undated (Box 22, Quarter inch audio reel 267_091)
  - Ritual All 770 III, Undated (Box 22, Quarter inch audio reel 267_092)
  - Ritual All 770 V, Undated; cuid30295 (Box 24, Quarter inch audio reel 267_116)
  - Ritual All 770 IV, Undated (Box 24, Quarter inch audio reel 267_085)
  - Ritual All 770 - The Songs, circa 1967-1970 (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_312, Box 13, Audiocassette 267_165)
    Audiocassette 267_312's label notes Songs 1 "Reading University Great Hall, Hammond Organ Harmoniums, Piano Percussion" and Songs 2 "Wesleyan University Connecticut, USA, Electric Piano, Electric Organ and Filters."
  - Ritual All 770 - The Songs - Irregular Pulses, Unique Marks, November, 1970 (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_211)
  - Ritual All 770 - Original Take of The Songs (Clean), 1967 (Box 23, Quarter inch audio reel 267_094)
  - Ritual All 770 - Rehearsal for The Songs, circa 1967 (Box 25, Quarter inch audio reel 267_057)
  - Roger Treiutley, Undated (Box 23, Quarter inch audio reel 267_063)
  - Rosalie Sorrels, Undated (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_193)
  - Sagging and Reading Room, Undated (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_312)
  - St. Mark's Performance - Stations of the Cross, June, 1974 (Box 14, Audiocassette 267_351)